# **Eunae Cho**

Cork, Ireland | Linkedin | (+353) 087-786-1804 | azureluster@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Meticulous, tech-savvy and pro-active *senior bilingual metadata specialist* with 3+ years of experience working for one of the Fortune 100 IT company on their on-demand video platform as a vendor employee. HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python coding understanding. 5 years of experience as a journalist in Banking, Gaming and IT Industry in South Korea.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Welocalize / RWS Moravia

Cork, Ireland

Bilingual Metadata Specialist

November 2019 – Present

- Analysing large-scale of media metadata & artworks for a fast growing on-demand video platform, working on average 100+ TV show/movie contents weekly using XML feed and internal tools.
- Managing and monitoring featured video contents as a senior member of featured content (FC) team, with keen eyes in detail, to have correct metadata and availability data delivered by communicating with partner operations and editorials before the contents being aired in a timely manner.
- Coaching and training 1~4 new hires, and delivering weekly troubleshooting exercise with tricky tasks to the team.
- Assisting project managers with creating template, project report, workflow enhancement using Quip and Confluence.
- Solving tickets related with metadata issue on end users by communicating with external partners, operations, editorials and engineers.
- Supplying objective feedbacks to various video broadcasting channels and partners that are providing contents to the platform, ensuring up-to-dated data be surfaced on the user environment before onboarding.
- Managing groups of 3~5 people to work on projects aimed to validate contents related with current entertainment events (e.g Golden Globe, Oscar etc), verifying the artwork/metadata to be correctly reflected on end users for different countries.
- Working with the highest productivity in the team, exceeding monthly KPI for more than 50%.
- Quality assurance checking on customer's environment tool for priority markets and altering low quality artwork/ metadata to develop greater customer experience.

Activision Dublin, Ireland

Localisation Quality Assurance Tester

July 2019 - November 2019

- Analysed quality of linguistic, visual and functional issues by playing video games targeted to launch in Korean market and reported critical issues to the engineers via JIRA in a timely manner.
- Investigated safety check for adolescent players such as dismemberment of a body, usage of drugs, nudity etc to meet the Korean regulation standard.
- Supported language specialists by providing fluent and smooth translation from English to Korean to avoid awkward translation mistakes.

Keywords Studios Dublin, Ireland

Localisation Quality Assurance Tester

May 2019 - June 2019

• Investigated linguistic and functional bugs while playing video/smartphone games and reported the issue for better amendments using JIRA by communicating with other teams.

Digital Times Seoul, Korea

Journalist

March 2018 – February 2019

- Covered news of monetary policy from Bank of Korea, and government financial decisions made by Ministry of Finance.
- Provided articles for easy understanding of difficult terminologies related with economic fields.

JTBC Plus Seoul, Korea

Journalist

*March* 2015 – *March* 2018

- Reported news of private banking industry, IT/gaming industry and distribution industry.
- Communicated with Public Relation (PR) team from various banking & distribution companies to sustain profitable relationship.
- Translated English articles to Korean from international news agencies such as AP, AFP etc.

## **EDUCATION**

### **Sungkyunkwan University**

Seoul, Korea

Bachelor's Degree in Economics & Political Science and International Relations Graduation Date: February 2013

• Student English News Reporter: 3 years as a student reporter in School English Magazine 'Sungkyun Times'.

### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

**Skills:** Microsoft Office (Excel, Words, PPT) | Confluence | SQL | XML | MacOS | HTML/CSS | Python | JavaScript **Language**: Korean (Native) | English (Full Professional Proficiency) | Japanese (Limited Working Proficiency) **Certificate**: Analyse Data with SQL Skill Path (Codecademy, 04.2022)

Interests: Validating data, Translation, Localisation, Coding, Blog Writer, Playing Guitar, PS4 & Xbox games